# 今天我朋友杰瑞从美国带了1个猪肉味的香肠
My friend Jerry brought me some sausages made of artificial pork from US
# 还有2个牛肉
...and two packs of "beef"
# 这个牛肉大概是什么价格
What's the price of the "beef" like?
# 这个是70人民币
This one costs around 70 yuan
# 70块人民币这里是500克吗
Is it 70 yuan for the 500 grams pack?
# 差不多
Basically
# 450克
it's 450 grams
# 哦 453克
ok, 453 grams
# 9两还没有1斤
About 9 liang (= 450g), yet to reach 1 jin (=500g)
# 这个我感觉在我们这里贵了差不多1倍
I think this is sold here at double of the price in the states
# 跟新鲜牛肉比贵了1倍
And it's still twice as expensive as fresh beef...
# 但是不知道做出来的味道是什么样子的
Not sure about how it will taste like after being cooked
# 待会儿吃了才知道划不划得来
Got to decide if it's worth buying after we try it
# 有可能比真的肉好吃吗
Could this taste better than real meat?
# 你觉得呢
What do you think?
# 这个颜色的话就像那个牛肉已经做熟了一样
The color of it resembles that of the cooked beef
# 新鲜的牛肉是红色的
Fresh beef is bright red
# 这个是暗红色的
This appears to have the color of dull-red
# 这个颜色比较暗
It's dimmer
# 这个香肠的话
As for the sausage
# 看起来还好
Looks not bad
# 可能加了一些香精
There might be some food additives
# 有猪肉的味道
It has the unique pork flavor to it
# 好 我们现在开始做一些菜
Alright, let's cook
# 这个香肠我打算用这个辣椒加这个蒜苗一起炒
I plan to cook the sausages with chili and garlic sprouts
# 做一个小炒香肠
The dish is called "Stir-fry Sausage"
# 然后这个牛肉的话用来烧豆腐
The artificial beef can be braised with tofu
# 做成麻婆豆腐
To make "Mapo Tofu"
# 这个的话我就切长豆角炒成肉末就行了
For the pork I'll mince it and cut up some cowpea for a stir-fry
# 你能吃辣吗
Can you eat spicy food?
# 能
I can
# 你能吃很辣吗
Too what degree?
# 很辣
Extra spicy
# 这个辣椒可是非常辣的哦
We are going to use very spicy chili though
# 不是这个
- Is this chili pepper?
- It's not.
# 这里有一种辣椒非常辣我怕你受不了
We have a very spicy kind of chili here, I'm afraid that you cannot bear it
# 可以可以我们可以吃一下
It's ok to try it
# 好 我们现在开始做
Fine, next up, cooking
# 先把这个切开
Cut this open
# 他有很多不一样的油比如椰子油
It includes various kinds of oil such as coconut oil
# 又很多椰子的油
Plenty of coconut oil
# 这个的油都是植物油是吧
Those are all vegetable oils, right?
# 嗯
Ye
# 那有什么 你可以吃
It doesn't matter--you can eat it raw
# 可以吃哈
Edible?
# 能吃
Edible!
# 你觉得是什么味道
What does it taste like?
# 真的牛肉没有这么嫩
Real beef isn't that tender
# 嗯
Positive
# 这个就像那个豆干
This actually tastes like hard bean curd
# 又有点像面筋
Somewhat similar to wheat gluten
# 这个用很多豆做的
It's made from lots of beans
# 豆子做的
beans?
# 怪不得
That's why
# 70块钱
For 70 yuan
# 我想不应该不会花70块钱人民币买还不带一斤的这个肉
I'm not likely to spend 70 yuan on barely 500 grams of artificial meat
# 为什么
Why
# 贵啊
Expensive!
# 然后香味也不够牛肉香
And it doesn't get all the flavors unique to real beef
# 嗯
Ok
# 这个现在说还为时过早
It's all too soon to judge
# 白色的
White colored
# 这个是椰子
This is coconut
# 椰子
coconut?
# 那为什么他们用这个 因为真的肉有一些是脂肪
- Why do they use this?
- Cuz there are fat content in the real meat
# 所以有一些是白色的
So some portions should be white
# 有一些是蛋白质
The rest is protein
# 所以他们用椰子让口感对上肉
They use coconut to mimic the taste and the look of meat
# 如果没有椰子就不像
It won't look realistic without coconuts
# 真的猪肉跟牛肉差别很大
Real pork looks quite different from beef
# 嗯
ok
# 它的颜色 还有肌纤维都完全不一样
Its color and muscle fiber do not look alike at all
# 包括味道
Also the flavor
# 完全不一样
It's totally different
# 等一下都吃完了我们现在开始切吧
We don't want to eat all of it raw, let's start cutting it
# 这个切起来很软
It feels too soft when cutting through
# 那为什么你切的这么好
but then you are doing a good job
# 因为我是厨师啊
That's because I do cooking for a living
# 1把菜刀走天下
Traveling around the world with one Kitchen Knife
# 美国的菜是不是很大根
Aren't the vegetables in the states larger?
# 美国的菜比中国的菜贵贵很多
Vegetables in the states cost much more than here
# 因为我们没有很多新鲜的菜
Because the consumers have little access to freshly picked vegetables
# 这个豆腐好大一块
A chunky tofu
# 今天中午用你的牛肉粒做一个麻婆豆腐
Gonna cook "Mapo Tofu" with that "beef" for lunch
# 好
Sounds good
# 用这么多豆腐
That's a lot of tofu
# 没关系我们人多嘛
No worry, we got a bunch of people around
# 你们美国的厨师可以这样切菜吗
Do US chefs cut in a similar why?
# 做这样的东西他们用一个机器
They use some kind of machine to do the job for them
# 他们基本上用一个机器来做这样的菜
They basically utilize machines to cook dishes like this
# 还有一些比较好的师傅他可以蒙上眼睛切
Some chefs with good knife skills can cut while blindfolded
#(sounds exactly like a senior chinese chef...)
# 你烧的燃吗 杰瑞
Are you able to start the fire? Jerry
# 要等一下
One sec.
# 我看一下
Let me take a look
# 哦 这个不够
Ok, this is insufficient
# 柴不够 多放一点
Not enough firewood, a bit more
# 好
ok
# 多放一点要不然又要熄了
Put more or the fire's gonna extinguish again
# 我们先做这个小炒猪肉
Let's do the "Stir-fry Pork" first
# 就是用辣椒和蒜苗一起炒
You cook the pork with chili and garlic sprouts
# 所以我们先炒辣椒
Let's start with chili pepepr
# 然后再倒这个
And add this in
# 这个一听起来就不是真的牛肉
The sound when cooking differs quite a lot from real beef
# 这个好了吗
It finished?
# 好啦
All good
# 你知道吗 麻婆豆腐是我最喜欢吃的菜
Do you know that Mapo Tofu is my favorite dish
# 是吗
for real?
# 对 所以我给你一点压力
This will have some pressure on you
# 嘿嘿
XD
# 还有这个肉
And the meat as well
# 然后再放一点花椒
Add some Sichuan peppercorn
# 可以多放
You can put more
# 等一下还要加的
Gonna add more later
# 好的
Ok
# 这个会非常的辣
This dish will be hot as hell
# 然后把这个豆腐放下去
Add the Tofu into the wok
# 起锅
Ready to serve
# 你确定你能吃很麻
You sure that you can bear the numbness?
# 嗯 喜欢
Well I love it
# 那好 我们多放一点
Alright, then we can add a bit more
# 这个撒在上面就很香的
Sprinkle this to enhance the fragrance
# 我们这个肉末一般酒店里面做的话是是先它腌好
The restaurant way to prepare the minced pork is to marinate it in advance
# 腌好了之后把它炒成半成品
After which it will be stir-fried to halfway done
# 基本上已经调好味了
And no more seasoning needed
# 然后我们家庭做的话都不用怎么去腌
You don't have to marinate it if the cooking is done at home
# 下到锅里面再调味
Season it in the wok
# 但是这个的话它已经是有一定的味道了
Since this meat seems to be already lightly seasoned
# 所以我们不需要加太多的调料进去
We don't have to add too much seasoning
# 然后同样的我们先炒这个
fry this first in a similar way
# 先炒辅料
Always cook auxiliary ingredients first
# 把这个炒到断生然后再放这个进去
Stir fry to a point that it's barely cooked, then add this in
# 这个很散不像刚才那个
This gets all scattered around unlike the previous one
# 那个牛肉一样
Unlike that beef
# 再放一些酱油就可以啦
Add some soy sauce and it will be good
# 尝一下嘛 吃嘛
Have a try. Try it
# 吃肉
Eat the meat
# 这个是肉
This is meat
# 这个是猪肉
This is pork
# 对 这是猪肉
right, this is pork
# 这是美国来的
This is from US
# 美国拿过来的吗
You brought it from US?
# 嗯
Ye
# 你觉得美国的猪肉怎么样
How do you like the US pork?
# 可以可以
Not bad
# 你应该吃这块最麻的
You can eat that one which is the numbest
# 这个已经有一点麻了对吧
This is already slightly numb I guess?
# 看我吃这个最麻的
Bear witness with me, I take the challenge
# 太麻啦
Too numb
# 他就喜欢吃麻的
He likes it
# 四伯爷来尝一下这个
Uncle try this one
# 这个是牛肉
It's American beef
# 跟中国的牛肉有什么区别
How does it compare to Chinese beef
# 美国的牛肉很脆
Crispy
# 是
Right
# 中国的牛肉很绵 就是有韧劲
Chinese beef are soft and chewy
# 四伯爷我给你说嘛
Uncle let me tell you the truth, the meat is artificial
# 这个肉是假的肉 不是正宗的牛肉
Not authentic beef, it's kinda faked
# 有很多不一样的豆子 还有很多蔬菜的蛋白质
Many different types of beans and proteins from vegetables
# 还有盐
And there is also salt
# 还有一点油
A fraction of oil
# 放在一起就是这样的
This is what it looks like when putting together
# 这个还没有一斤就要70块钱
This barely weighs 500 grams , however it's sold at the price of 70 yuan
# 哇 好贵呀
Wow, quite expensive
# 你觉得哪一个更好吃 这个和中国的牛肉
Which one tastes better to you? The Chinese ones or this one?
# 中国的牛肉吃起来很紧
The Chinese beef tastes more chewy
# 这个牛肉吃起来很松
This kind of beef tastes loose
# 比较起来这个牛肉很脆
Another difference is the crispiness which normal beef doesn't have
# 让你买的话你会买哪个
Which one will you choose if you want to get some beef
# 我肯定买真的撒
I'll definitely go with the real beef
# 如果说价钱一样的你买哪个
What if they are sold at the same price point
# 价钱一样的我也都肯买中国的真牛肉、
I'll buy the real beef even if the prices are the same
# 要吃货真价实的
Gonna eat the real things
# 有些人喜欢买这个 很多超市都卖完了
Some people prefer this, it is sold out at a number of supermarkets
# 他们的工厂很小
They had only limited production power
# 他们现在已经是上市公司
And they have gone public
# 上市公司 在我们中国是不行的
Public company? Not saleable in China!
# 他是要倒霉的
Unfortunately
# 他这样做要倒闭
The factory will go bankrupt
# 在你们哪里这个好卖我觉得
About why it's selling well in your place, I think
# 我个人猜想一下
I'll take a guess
# 会不会是因为这个人造肉里面少一些风险
It might be because that artificial meat represents a low-risk alternative?
# 会少一些其它不好的细菌之类的东西
Because it's likely more sanitized
# 又或者是说满足你们那边的素质主义
Or it could be specially made for vegetarians in your country
# 就是不吃肉的他也可以吃这种植物做的肉
...as vegetarians are able to eat this kind of meat made from plants
# 主要是支持吃素的人或者喜欢这个有文化
For the most part, it is Vegetarians or people that are into the vegetarianism culture that are buying this
# 很多人觉得如果你做这样的你应该有文化是比较高级的人
If you are consuming artificial meant, many people would consider you as a "man of culture", or someone that is on another level
# 因为很多人觉得如果做这样的肉是对哦世界比较好
They think that the world will be a better place if people turn to artificial meat
# 所以他们的朋友就觉得他们很有意思
This is the topic of conversation that can make your popular among your friends
# 虽然说在我们这个地方行不通
well, it does not seem to work here
# 但是也很感激杰瑞
But huge thanks to Jerry my man
# 从美国那么远带过来让给我们尝一下这个味道
Who brought this all the way from America to let us have a change to taste it
# 我觉得本来这个东西本来一般般
Well this is just some average food that we have
# 这个人造肉做得一般般
It's not some delicious ingredient to begin with
# 但是用你的方法真的让这个好吃
But you definitely make it taste fantastic with your culinary skills
# 有可能从来没有1个人做人造肉跟你一样这么好吃
There was never ever a person that can turn artificial meat into a delicacy as you did
# 真的 你是第一个
You are the first one on the earth to accomplish that